BRIAN THOMPSON Lead Software Engineer

(636)426-0447

St. Louis, MO

brianrobt@pm.me

github.com/brianrobt

/in/brian-r-thompson

SUMMARY

First and foremost, I value hard work, honesty, and grit. I love being in a team where I can contribute my expertise while simultaneously learning new things and growing my skillset. While I'm not honing my craft, I'm either with my wife and children, walking our dog, at the gym, or reading about history and philosophy.

SKILLS

Python, Java, Groovy, Ruby, JavaScript, Languages:

TypeScript, Bash, SQL

Technologies: AWS, Azure, Docker, Terraform, Jenkins,

SaltStack, Gradle, Maven, Chef, Linux, Git,

Tomcat, Apache, JBoss

EDUCATION

2008-2014

Truman State University B.S. Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

6/2022 - 2/2024 **Lead Site Reliability Engineer**

Mastercard

- Configuration, maintenance, management, deployment, and high-availability uptime of over 100 Thales Luna HSMs, and 50+ supporting virtual machines.
- · Lead the design and implementation of the company-wide Luna HSM AWS Hybrid Cloud initiative.
- Mentored and supported junior team members every day.
- · Developed and designed automation solutions, including writing Python packages, Jenkins pipelines, shell scripts, Chef cookbooks, and other custom tools from scratch.
- · Wrote and maintained detailed technical documentation, including operational procedures, designs, and infrastructure lists.
- Managed and improved change processes for Luna HSMs and supporting infrastructure.
- Managed stakeholders interests while keeping the operational interests at heart.
- Developed Luna HSM operational design for a hybrid environment (on-prem HSMs and clients in AWS/Azure).
- Lead the migration of Azure VMs from CentOS 7 to RHEL 8 for my team.
- Collaborated with dozens of different stakeholders and individuals from other teams across the company on a daily basis.
- Increased procedural speed without sacrificing quality.
- Provided a solid, reliable, and streamlined customer experience.
- Improved production deployment and operational efficiencies for a widely used shared micro service.
- Wrote audit reports, and addressed gaps to meet audit requirements.
- Lead cloud operations for a widely used cryptography microservice.
- Performed application deployments and infrastructure management in Azure with Terraform.

10/2021 - 4/2022

Cloud Data Engineer

Ameren

- · Configured and automated AWS infrastructure using Terraform (including AWS RedShift, IAM, SSO, Cloud-Front, Lambda, S3, and RDS).
- · Developed and delivered multiple Databricks pipelines that transformed raw data into usable, formatted data that could then be used by the Data Scientists.
- · Designed and implemented an AD-based security strategy so that the Data Scientists could use Databricks in a controlled manner.

Mastercard

- Specialized in Application Release Automation (ARA).
- · Maintained custom SaltStack modules for deploying applications to various middleware components (e.g., Apache, Tomcat, JBoss, WebSphere).
- Wrote extensive unit and integration tests.
- Worked with development teams to create and prioritize new features.
- · Maintained supporting infrastructure with Chef Cookbooks.
- Built a new ARA framework from scratch with Chef Habitat.
- Migrated the existing ARA SaltStack solution to the new Chef Habitat framework.
- Wrote and maintained Jenkins pipelines, shared libraries, and job templates.
- · Used Splunk to monitor infrastructure health and gather usage metrics of the various ARA modules.

3/2017 - 11/2018 **Software Engineer**

Mastercard

- Built an application for bank customers that netted \$400m USD in the first year after release.
- Worked on a suite of web applications that were directly used by customers in production.
- Wrote a UI in Angular (from Alpha release to 6.0).
- Collaborated on feature development and design.
- Wrote a transacations-based web service in Java.
- Spun up a Jenkins server for team's immediate use before Jenkins was widespread across the corporation.
- Dedicated an RHEL VM internally exposed to the company since multiple teams demanded its usage.
- Managed LDAP roles and permissions.
- Created a Git branching strategy that the team still uses today.

7/2015 - 3/2017

Associate Software Engineer

Mastercard

- Ported an internal Java CLI tool to an AngularJS web app and a RESTful Java API.
- Designed a GUI from wireframes to implementation.
- Used many AngularJS (1.x) modules to manage common tasks like routing, web services, and animations.

6/2012 - 3/2015

Junior Software Engineer (Intern)

Tapestry Solutions

I was an intern at Tapestry Solutions in 2012, which changed to a part-time role while I was finishing up school. I stayed at the company until a few months after I graduated.

While I was there, I worked with Hudson/Jenkins, Kettle (an ETL tool), AWS (EC2 and S3), Java, Bash, and Linux. My role was heavy with automating tasks that the more experienced team needed. The company had a requirement that you had to have at least 10 years of experience and be high-performing. I was the first intern there. It was a great learning experience working with engineers that were so much more experienced than myself, and helped jump-start my career significantly.

LANGUAGES

English - Native, Spanish - Intermediate